<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>We launch on Friday</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content on We launch on Friday</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Jun 2022 14:06:26 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>What We Cannot Know</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/book/what-we-cannot-know/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jun 2022 14:06:26 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/book/what-we-cannot-know/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Initially when I first saved it to the queue I thought the book would be about thinking, how to argue, how to read books and news. I didn&amp;rsquo;t even read the description of the book before I started listening to it. And boy was I pleasantly surprised by the contents. Topics ranging from the formation of the Universe, black holes and their event horizons, information and knowledge theory, theology, and human brain.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sourdough Starter Using Estonian Flour</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2022/05/sourdough-starter-using-estonian-flour/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2022 21:54:47 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2022/05/sourdough-starter-using-estonian-flour/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Updated: 29 December, 2022&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been baking sourdough bread on and off for almost 7 years now. And during those years there were so many failed&#xA;attempts that made me rage quit the whole process and throw my starter in the bin, only to calm down few months later&#xA;and start from scratch. I tried to be systematical and change ingredients and processes. I used different flours:&#xA;all brands of Estonian flour, Italian flour, Georgian flour. I used filtered water, bottled water, regular water. I&#xA;endlessly watched YouTube, read online, consulted friends, and took a course. And it still didn&amp;rsquo;t work. Until it finally&#xA;did. It was the starter.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Black Water Lilies</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/book/black-water-lilies/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2022 22:15:38 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/book/black-water-lilies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;impressions&#34;&gt;Impressions&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I enjoyed listening to this book. It keeps you hooked to the story and has several plot twists.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-i-discovered-it&#34;&gt;How I discovered it?&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It was suggested by the audiobook app that I use. After listening to too many self-development books I decided to&#xA;take a break and enjoy some fiction. And why not listen to a novel with a good rating.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;summary--notes&#34;&gt;Summary + Notes&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Apart from an interesting narration that I thoroughly enjoyed, the story is told by 3 women living in the same small&#xA;town in Northern France, one thing that really caught my mind and made have goosebumps is the description of a murder.&#xA;An 11 year old child killed his fellow classmate. The horror in the victim&amp;rsquo;s eyes perfectly described by the author,&#xA;and the smile on the face of the killer brought the movie &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/City_of_God_(2002_film)&#34;&gt;City Of God&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;to my memories.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Summary May 2022</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2022/05/summary-may-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2022 21:51:53 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2022/05/summary-may-2022/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;birthday&#34;&gt;Birthday&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been the 2nd time I celebrated my birthday with friends since I became 18. And yet again it felt weird, scary,&#xA;and unnecessary until we actually met.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We first went to the escape room after which spent the evening in a local pub chatting on random things.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;sports&#34;&gt;Sports&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A colleague of mine started a challenge in Strava in order to get everyone moving. And surprisingly it worked. Not because&#xA;I feel competitive or that I pass or get passed by other colleagues in the leaderboard, but simply because others are&#xA;doing sports and I feel like I need to do too.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Summary April 2022</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2022/05/summary-april-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2022 21:51:48 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2022/05/summary-april-2022/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently I realised that I put too much attention on the negative things completely ignoring big and small wins. As a&#xA;result life seems like a never-ending misery. Yet I have a lot to celebrate. Just not in April.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Summary March 2022</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2022/04/summary-march-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2022 21:45:42 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2022/04/summary-march-2022/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;appearance-on-the-tv&#34;&gt;Appearance on the TV&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Out of curiosity and willingness to experience what it&amp;rsquo;s like to speak on the television, I went to talk about&#xA;anti-money laundering and &lt;a href=&#34;https://salv.com&#34;&gt;Salv&lt;/a&gt; on the &amp;ldquo;Morning Coffee&amp;rdquo; programme on ERR. This is a local TV&#xA;station broadcasting in Russian.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I had about 5 minutes of fame during which my heart was beating like crazy, yet after watching the recording myself&#xA;it looked like I was absolutely calm.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Time Machine</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/book/the-time-machine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2022 16:26:51 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/book/the-time-machine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;impressions&#34;&gt;Impressions&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This has been my first fiction book after a long pause, and I enjoyed it thoroughly. As a university student I remember&#xA;reading Arthur Clarke&amp;rsquo;s novels and dreaming of the future, what it would be like. And The Time Machine brought me back&#xA;those memories again. I also loved the almost long-lost feeling of not wanting to stop reading because it was so&#xA;interesting.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The book raises some interesting questions like where does capitalism and a never-ending desire to buy more goods and&#xA;live an ever more comfortable life leads us. One option, as the author says, could be that we eventually stop at any&#xA;progress and just start enjoying life all day every day. There won&amp;rsquo;t be any problems getting food, clothes, or other&#xA;necessities, there won&amp;rsquo;t be any work needed. Think of people as pets, or livestock, which are enjoying the grass and&#xA;shelter. In the absence of external risk factors we stop evolving, and it seems that dreaming too, which reminded&#xA;me Nassim Taleb&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Antifragile_(book)&#34;&gt;Antifragile&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Summary February 2022</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2022/03/summary-february-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2022 21:11:58 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2022/03/summary-february-2022/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was hesitating whether I should write my monthly report again or not. This time it was for a completely different reason.&#xA;February turned up to be one of the lowest point in my life emotionally.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the beginning of the month I contracted Covid from my daughter who got it in the kindergarten. Almost by chance I&#xA;decided to make a rapid test because I didn&amp;rsquo;t sleep well during the night. And the test came out positive. In 10 minutes&#xA;all my emergency things were packed and I left to my sister&amp;rsquo;s home who at the time was abroad. Midway I got a call&#xA;that my daughter was also positive, and so we left to isolate together.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Summary January 2022</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2022/02/summary-january-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Feb 2022 14:30:04 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2022/02/summary-january-2022/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;January has been full of events, big and small.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-dog-which-almost-happened&#34;&gt;A dog which almost happened.&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One of my big lifetime dreams since childhood has been to have a dog. First my parents didn&amp;rsquo;t allow to have one. In fact&#xA;I think I didn&amp;rsquo;t even ask or insist much, maybe once. We had a very modest income in the family, and there wasn&amp;rsquo;t much&#xA;left to feed another family member. Then I grew up and went to study in the University and didn&amp;rsquo;t have time and enough&#xA;responsibility to take care of anyone other than myself. Long story short, after moving to the place where I currently&#xA;live, I started thinking of getting a dog.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Summary December 2021</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2022/01/summary-december-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jan 2022 21:23:15 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2022/01/summary-december-2021/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This one is very late, and since yet again I haven&amp;rsquo;t taken any notes of what&amp;rsquo;s been happening in December, I have already&#xA;forgotten everything. To be frank, there hasn&amp;rsquo;t been much to talk about either with one notable exception: I was asleep&#xA;at 11 in the evening.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I also started taking more daily notes of some thoughts using Day One app on the phone. I was sold by the reminder feature.&#xA;One day when my younger child was particularly bad during the night, and as a result I was badly deprived of sleep the&#xA;following day. At first I wanted to erase that memory from my head, but then decided that instead I want to get reminded&#xA;of how bad it was the previous year so that I could enjoy the moment I&amp;rsquo;ll be in a year&amp;rsquo;s time (hopefully). And that&#xA;is how I started journalling almost daily now.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Greatest Story Ever Told — So Far</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/book/the-greatest-story-ever-told-so-far/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Dec 2021 13:53:54 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/book/the-greatest-story-ever-told-so-far/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-book-in-3-sentences&#34;&gt;The book in 3 sentences&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The history of scientific discoveries is very exciting and is built on the work of hundreds of people. Einstein didn&amp;rsquo;t come up with his theories out of nowhere, he was standing on the shoulders of others before him. So did Faraday,&#xA;Curie, Feynman, and every other scientist.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;One of the biggest reasons driving scientist is the desire to figure uncover the ways nature works&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve managed to connect the three main forces into a single theory, but gravity still evades it. And so the search continues.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;impressions&#34;&gt;Impressions&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It took a very long time to read this book. On my first run when I was almost halfway through it I started all over again because I already forgot what I was reading about. So every new concept, every discovery, every theory - I went to Wikipedia and YouTube to learn about these. And yet there still were many theories and explanations left that evaded my understanding. However I now now much more about the quantum physics, virtual particles, what was all the fuzz surrounding the discovery of Higg&amp;rsquo;s Boson. And more importantly: what the Large Hadron Collider will be doing after the discovery (I thought the sole purpose of it was finding the God&amp;rsquo;s particle).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Summary November 2021</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2021/12/summary-november-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2021 18:41:37 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2021/12/summary-november-2021/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;work&#34;&gt;Work&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been two months now since I&amp;rsquo;ve started worked full-time in another place while also supporting and continuing to&#xA;build &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.getshipit.com&#34;&gt;shipit&lt;/a&gt;. Having a new job is already stressful enough, but having two jobs in addition&#xA;to a family with two children is&amp;hellip; Well, it&amp;rsquo;s really hard.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On my new job I&amp;rsquo;m learning a completely tech stack on top of a fairly complicated business logic. The last time I felt&#xA;useless like that was about 8 or so years ago when I joined another startup and just moved from developing small websites&#xA;in PHP to working on a big monolith in Python.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Summary October 2021</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2021/11/summary-october-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Nov 2021 11:18:20 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2021/11/summary-october-2021/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;October was the first month when I had to leave full-time development of shipit and move to another job. I am now a product engineer at &lt;a href=&#34;https://salv.com&#34;&gt;Salv&lt;/a&gt; which helps companies beat financial crime. As unfortunately happens with many startups, shipit somewhat failed financially. In the past year being the only full-time employee also had its toll on me: depression and anxiety, personal pressure to improve the situation. After almost 7 years of remote work I now go to the office, have small talk and very deep and insightful conversation, walk way more, and overall have a happier life. And for now shipit becomes a side project with continued support and slightly slower feature development.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cultivating your children</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2021/10/cultivating-your-children/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Oct 2021 12:22:42 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2021/10/cultivating-your-children/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A while ago I went to the movie theater to see &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dune_(2021_film)&#34;&gt;Dune&lt;/a&gt;. I quite liked&#xA;the film but wasn&amp;rsquo;t blown away by it. In school I played &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dune_II&#34;&gt;the game&lt;/a&gt; on my&#xA;Sega Mega Drive. However after the cinema experience I had the itch to &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/book/dune/&#34;&gt;read the novel&lt;/a&gt; and learn more&#xA;about the characters.  After all, there are a lot of important things that are in the book but are always missing from&#xA;the screen adaptation. And boy was I blown away&amp;hellip; I am still just half way through the first book, so this is not a&#xA;book review but rather some thoughts I got about raising your children. With that in mind, let&amp;rsquo;s move on.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dune</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/book/dune/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2021 21:31:51 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/book/dune/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I haven&amp;rsquo;t read this book until the end, and finished roughly where the movie ended. This is not because it&amp;rsquo;s not worth&#xA;the time or not interesting at all. On the contrary, the book is way more thoughtful and exciting than the movie. The&#xA;reason I took the book in the first place was to read on the topic of upbringing children. How royal children are&#xA;raised and what they are taught. What they feel. And in that sence I&amp;rsquo;ve got enough answers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wildcrafted Fermentation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/book/wildcrafted-fermentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2021 21:30:21 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/book/wildcrafted-fermentation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-book-in-3-sentences&#34;&gt;The book in 3 sentences&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Explore your local environment.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;There are way more edible plants just next to your home than you can imagine.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Lacto-fermentation is not limited to sauerkraut only but can be used to make roots, non-dairy cheeses, drinks, and much more.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;impressions&#34;&gt;Impressions&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Was it good? Was it bad? What did I feel? What I liked&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-i-discovered-it&#34;&gt;How I discovered it?&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been following foraging and fermnetation subreddits for a long time, and every now and then Pascal Baudar&amp;rsquo;s name is mentioned. I decided to get this book when someone&#xA;mentioned it again in relation to non-dairy cheeses (which are actually made of fermented nuts).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Summary September 2021</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2021/10/summary-september-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Oct 2021 10:59:09 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2021/10/summary-september-2021/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;September was all about job interviews and a bit of travelling.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;job&#34;&gt;Job&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After being out of the job market for nearly a decade (I got jobs via personal connections), this month I started actively looking for work. It&amp;rsquo;s a weird feeling because all those years I&amp;rsquo;ve been interviewing people myself, and&#xA;now I had to switch sides. Turns out we currently live in the golden age of software engineering jobs where every developer can almost auction themselves for potential employers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nullius in Verba</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2021/10/nullius-in-verba/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Oct 2021 10:40:23 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2021/10/nullius-in-verba/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While this is not a full blog post, I wanted to remember the motto of the Royal Society:&#xA;&amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nullius_in_verba&#34;&gt;Nullius in Verba&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; which in Latin means &amp;ldquo;Take nobody&amp;rsquo;s word for it&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;These days this phrase is more important than ever and critical thinking seems to be the lot of minority as neither&#xA;schools nor universities teach that.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Summary August 2021</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2021/08/summary-august-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2021 13:26:07 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2021/08/summary-august-2021/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;public-speaking&#34;&gt;Public speaking&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/public-speaking-elm.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Elm Programming&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Probably the biggest event for me this month was me speaking on the local &lt;a href=&#34;http://devclub.eu/&#34;&gt;developers meetup&lt;/a&gt;.&#xA;It&amp;rsquo;s been almost 2 years since I took public speaking course, and thanks to all of the lockdowns I haven&amp;rsquo;t been able&#xA;to practice these my skills. After much hesitation I sent the proposal and it got accepted.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Having gone through the learning part before, I prepared the slide deck, the story, came up with some jokes, and practiced&#xA;several times in front of the family and one of the organizers. Yet no matter how much you practice and perfect the&#xA;presentation there&amp;rsquo;s still this fear of the unknown. And I won&amp;rsquo;t be me without a fuckup.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Summary July 2021</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2021/08/summary-july-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 20:53:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2021/08/summary-july-2021/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;flyboarding&#34;&gt;Flyboarding&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Probably the most memorable event of July was me trying flyboarding. It&amp;rsquo;s a type of water sports where you put your legs&#xA;into a board with two pipes that blast water. This water is pumped through the pipe connected to a water jet, and as&#xA;a result you can hover over the water.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img width=&#34;400&#34; src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/flyboarding.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Flyboarding&#34; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Before the event I was somewhat nervous: who wants to spend 20-25 minutes constantly falling into the water? Not me,&#xA;that&amp;rsquo;s for sure. Turned out though that either it is fairly easy, or I am just good at holding the balance. After few&#xA;minutes I managed to stand straight. The next 5 minutes I was going circles and getting used to the 5-10 meter height I&#xA;was above the water. Finally, the remaining 15 or so minutes I was attempting to do some tricks: &amp;ldquo;making jumps&amp;rdquo; by&#xA;first going down and then using the momentum going high up, diving like a dolphin, and doing spins.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Summary June 2021</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2021/07/summary-june-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jul 2021 09:54:40 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2021/07/summary-june-2021/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;math-course&#34;&gt;Math course&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A while ago I have signed up for an online Maths course. I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking about getting back to university to study&#xA;maths for the past 2-3 years, and eventually decided to refresh the knowledge by taking the free course. It started&#xA;in June and after the initial assignment I dropped out. Why?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The curriculum is really interesting, and so are the teachers. In the first week I spent about an hour every day to&#xA;go through the problems, and while sad to admit it, I simply do not have enough time right now.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Human Hacking</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/book/human-hacking/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jun 2021 15:23:50 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/book/human-hacking/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-book-in-3-sentences&#34;&gt;The book in 3 sentences&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;This is a book in short&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Highlight number two&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Highlight number three&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;impressions&#34;&gt;Impressions&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Was it good? Was it bad? What did I feel? What I liked&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-i-discovered-it&#34;&gt;How I discovered it?&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Asked on Twitter for book recommendations on social engineering for complete beginners, and this came out on top.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-it-changed-me&#34;&gt;How it changed me&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;it made me more anxious&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;it made me happier&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-top-quotes&#34;&gt;My top quotes&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Quote 1&#xA;continuing&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How I Consume Books</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2021/06/how-i-consume-books/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Jun 2021 09:37:15 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2021/06/how-i-consume-books/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;These days paper is not the only medium one can use to &amp;ldquo;read&amp;rdquo; books. There are e-book readers like Kindle. There are&#xA;audio books from services like Audible. There are apps on the phone to read books. And there are apps which can read&#xA;you e-books. So saying that you&amp;rsquo;ve just read a book might not be technically correct which is why I opted to used the&#xA;word &amp;ldquo;consume&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I have my books in 3 different mediums:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Letters to Serena</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/book/letters-to-serena/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jun 2021 21:22:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/book/letters-to-serena/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-book-in-3-sentences&#34;&gt;The book in 3 sentences&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;This is a book in short&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Highlight number two&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Highlight number three&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;impressions&#34;&gt;Impressions&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Was it good? Was it bad? What did I feel? What I liked&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-i-discovered-it&#34;&gt;How I discovered it?&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Via reference from another book&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-it-changed-me&#34;&gt;How it changed me&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;it made me more anxious&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;it made me happier&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-top-quotes&#34;&gt;My top quotes&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Quote 1&#xA;continuing&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is quote number 2&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;summary--notes&#34;&gt;Summary + Notes&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;this is a note&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Living My Life</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/book/living-my-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jun 2021 21:19:37 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/book/living-my-life/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-book-in-3-sentences&#34;&gt;The book in 3 sentences&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;This is a book in short&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Highlight number two&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Highlight number three&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;impressions&#34;&gt;Impressions&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Was it good? Was it bad? What did I feel? What I liked&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-i-discovered-it&#34;&gt;How I discovered it?&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Like &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/book/letters-to-a-young-poet/&#34;&gt;Letters To a Young Poet&lt;/a&gt;, I discovered this book in a hacking manual.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-it-changed-me&#34;&gt;How it changed me&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;it made me more anxious&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;it made me happier&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-top-quotes&#34;&gt;My top quotes&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Quote 1&#xA;continuing&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is quote number 2&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Days of War Nights of Love</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/book/days-of-war-nights-of-love/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jun 2021 21:15:50 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/book/days-of-war-nights-of-love/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-book-in-3-sentences&#34;&gt;The book in 3 sentences&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;This is a book in short&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Highlight number two&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Highlight number three&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;impressions&#34;&gt;Impressions&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Was it good? Was it bad? What did I feel? What I liked&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-i-discovered-it&#34;&gt;How I discovered it?&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Like &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/book/letters-to-a-young-poet/&#34;&gt;Letters To a Young Poet&lt;/a&gt;, I discovered this book in a hacking manual.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-it-changed-me&#34;&gt;How it changed me&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;it made me more anxious&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;it made me happier&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-top-quotes&#34;&gt;My top quotes&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Quote 1&#xA;continuing&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is quote number 2&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Momo</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/book/momo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jun 2021 21:11:45 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/book/momo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-book-in-3-sentences&#34;&gt;The book in 3 sentences&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;This is a book in short&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Highlight number two&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Highlight number three&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;impressions&#34;&gt;Impressions&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Was it good? Was it bad? What did I feel? What I liked&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-i-discovered-it&#34;&gt;How I discovered it?&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Like &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/book/letters-to-a-young-poet/&#34;&gt;Letters To a Young Poet&lt;/a&gt;, I discovered this book in a hacking manual.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-it-changed-me&#34;&gt;How it changed me&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;it made me more anxious&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;it made me happier&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-top-quotes&#34;&gt;My top quotes&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Quote 1&#xA;continuing&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is quote number 2&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Letters to a Young Poet</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/book/letters-to-a-young-poet/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jun 2021 20:53:56 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/book/letters-to-a-young-poet/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This isn&amp;rsquo;t a book per se but rather a collection of letters that Rainer Maria Rilke wrote Franz Kappus, a 19 year old&#xA;young man who was about to go to the army.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The whole collection is available &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.carrothers.com/rilke_main.htm&#34;&gt;online&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I listened to an audio version of this book, and after finishing it its contents quickly perished. Yet, I enjoyed&#xA;listening it without remembering a thing. I bought a paper version of this book and gifted it to a friend only to&#xA;realise that I want to re-read it myself on paper. I want to go over it slowly digesting every letter. So I am leaving&#xA;these TODOs in the hope to return here again.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Six Easy Pieces</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/book/six-easy-pieces/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jun 2021 20:52:44 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/book/six-easy-pieces/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-book-in-3-sentences&#34;&gt;The book in 3 sentences&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;This is a book in short&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Highlight number two&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Highlight number three&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;impressions&#34;&gt;Impressions&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Was it good? Was it bad? What did I feel? What I liked&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-i-discovered-it&#34;&gt;How I discovered it?&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Via reference from another book&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-it-changed-me&#34;&gt;How it changed me&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;it made me more anxious&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;it made me happier&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-top-quotes&#34;&gt;My top quotes&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Quote 1&#xA;continuing&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is quote number 2&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;summary--notes&#34;&gt;Summary + Notes&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;this is a note&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thing Explainer</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/book/thing-explainer/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jun 2021 20:49:15 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/book/thing-explainer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-book-in-3-sentences&#34;&gt;The book in 3 sentences&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;This is a book in short&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Highlight number two&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Highlight number three&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;impressions&#34;&gt;Impressions&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Was it good? Was it bad? What did I feel? What I liked&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-i-discovered-it&#34;&gt;How I discovered it?&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Via reference from another book&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-it-changed-me&#34;&gt;How it changed me&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;it made me more anxious&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;it made me happier&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-top-quotes&#34;&gt;My top quotes&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Quote 1&#xA;continuing&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is quote number 2&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;summary--notes&#34;&gt;Summary + Notes&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;this is a note&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thinking Physics</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/book/thinking-physics/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jun 2021 20:47:14 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/book/thinking-physics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-book-in-3-sentences&#34;&gt;The book in 3 sentences&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;This is a book in short&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Highlight number two&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Highlight number three&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;impressions&#34;&gt;Impressions&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Was it good? Was it bad? What did I feel? What I liked&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-i-discovered-it&#34;&gt;How I discovered it?&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Via reference from another book&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-it-changed-me&#34;&gt;How it changed me&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;it made me more anxious&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;it made me happier&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-top-quotes&#34;&gt;My top quotes&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Quote 1&#xA;continuing&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is quote number 2&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;summary--notes&#34;&gt;Summary + Notes&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;this is a note&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Story of Philosophy</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/book/the-story-of-philosophy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jun 2021 20:46:02 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/book/the-story-of-philosophy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-book-in-3-sentences&#34;&gt;The book in 3 sentences&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;This is a book in short&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Highlight number two&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Highlight number three&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;impressions&#34;&gt;Impressions&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Was it good? Was it bad? What did I feel? What I liked&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-i-discovered-it&#34;&gt;How I discovered it?&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Via reference from another book&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-it-changed-me&#34;&gt;How it changed me&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;it made me more anxious&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;it made me happier&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-top-quotes&#34;&gt;My top quotes&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Quote 1&#xA;continuing&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is quote number 2&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;summary--notes&#34;&gt;Summary + Notes&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;this is a note&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Masters of Disaster: The Ten Commandments of Damage Control</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/book/masters-of-disaster-the-ten-commandments-of-damage-control/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jun 2021 20:41:14 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/book/masters-of-disaster-the-ten-commandments-of-damage-control/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-book-in-3-sentences&#34;&gt;The book in 3 sentences&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;This is a book in short&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Highlight number two&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Highlight number three&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;impressions&#34;&gt;Impressions&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Was it good? Was it bad? What did I feel? What I liked&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-i-discovered-it&#34;&gt;How I discovered it?&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Via reference from another book&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-it-changed-me&#34;&gt;How it changed me&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;it made me more anxious&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;it made me happier&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-top-quotes&#34;&gt;My top quotes&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Quote 1&#xA;continuing&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is quote number 2&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;summary--notes&#34;&gt;Summary + Notes&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;this is a note&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Beginning of Infinity</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/book/the-beginning-of-infinity/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jun 2021 20:38:43 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/book/the-beginning-of-infinity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-book-in-3-sentences&#34;&gt;The book in 3 sentences&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;This is a book in short&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Highlight number two&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Highlight number three&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;impressions&#34;&gt;Impressions&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Was it good? Was it bad? What did I feel? What I liked&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-i-discovered-it&#34;&gt;How I discovered it?&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Via reference from another book&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-it-changed-me&#34;&gt;How it changed me&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;it made me more anxious&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;it made me happier&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-top-quotes&#34;&gt;My top quotes&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Quote 1&#xA;continuing&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is quote number 2&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;summary--notes&#34;&gt;Summary + Notes&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;this is a note&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Fabric of Reality</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/book/the-fabric-of-reality/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jun 2021 20:35:40 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/book/the-fabric-of-reality/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-book-in-3-sentences&#34;&gt;The book in 3 sentences&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;This is a book in short&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Highlight number two&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Highlight number three&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;impressions&#34;&gt;Impressions&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Was it good? Was it bad? What did I feel? What I liked&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-i-discovered-it&#34;&gt;How I discovered it?&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Via reference from another book&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-it-changed-me&#34;&gt;How it changed me&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;it made me more anxious&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;it made me happier&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-top-quotes&#34;&gt;My top quotes&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Quote 1&#xA;continuing&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is quote number 2&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;summary--notes&#34;&gt;Summary + Notes&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;this is a note&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Genome: The Autobiography of a Species in 23 Chapters</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/book/genome-the-autobiography-of-a-species-in-23-chapters/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jun 2021 16:44:01 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/book/genome-the-autobiography-of-a-species-in-23-chapters/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-book-in-3-sentences&#34;&gt;The book in 3 sentences&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;TODO&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;TODO&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;TODO&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;impressions&#34;&gt;Impressions&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;TODO&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-i-discovered-it&#34;&gt;How I discovered it?&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I listened to an &lt;a href=&#34;https://nav.al/matt-ridley&#34;&gt;episode&lt;/a&gt; of Naval&amp;rsquo;s podcast where&#xA;he discussed innovation with Matt Ridley. From their conversation I learned about&#xA;another book of Matt about the genome which excited me and prompted to read it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-it-changed-me&#34;&gt;How it changed me&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;TODO&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;TODO&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-top-quotes&#34;&gt;My top quotes&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;TODO&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;summary--notes&#34;&gt;Summary + Notes&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;TODO&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Summary May 2021</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2021/05/summary-may-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 May 2021 10:11:35 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2021/05/summary-may-2021/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;birthday-celebration&#34;&gt;Birthday celebration&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My last birthday celebration happened when I was 17 years old. I must say that the last as it was organized by me where&#xA;I actually invited friends to come. Since then my friends and family did congratulate me, and did celebrate it with me&#xA;every year, but it was always triggered by them, not me. I have a weird relationship to this &amp;ldquo;special&amp;rdquo; day which feels&#xA;nothing special for me. In fact, only my mum celebrates her own birthday, but not my dad nor my sister. And I think that&#xA;had an impact on me too: why bother? What&amp;rsquo;s so special about this day? Well, this year I changed my mind. Actually, it&#xA;was my wife who suggested to invite friends over, and I did.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Summary April 2021</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2021/04/summary-april-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Apr 2021 14:22:08 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2021/04/summary-april-2021/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;April wasn&amp;rsquo;t that much different from March, however few events worth mentioning.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;coffee-machine&#34;&gt;Coffee machine&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I bought an espresso machine. For a person who hated coffee his entire life this is a big thing. I never understood the&#xA;obsession with which people drink it. Occasionally I forced myself to drink it during some social meetings or when I needed&#xA;to work but was about to fall asleep. And every time it was cappuccino with lots of sugar to hide the taste of coffee.&#xA;But everything changed last year.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Telegram Is the New Rss Reader</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2021/03/telegram-is-the-new-rss-reader/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 10:10:30 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2021/03/telegram-is-the-new-rss-reader/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With Google killing its Reader an era ended for me. I loved its old design and couldn&amp;rsquo;t get used to the new alternatives.&#xA;As a result, I stopped reading blogs via RSS for some time. There was also a problem of information overload: too many&#xA;new posts, sort of like an infinite scroll in Facebook or Instagram.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Eventually a lot of interesting people I follow started creating channels in Telegram. And as of today, Telegram has&#xA;become a de-facto social network and news aggregator for me. Some of the things I have there:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Long Project Tracking</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2021/03/long-project-tracking/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 10:17:58 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2021/03/long-project-tracking/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been 6 months since I started it semi-actively. Between work, two kids, and all of the isolation I&amp;rsquo;ve managed to&#xA;find maybe an hour of time every month to work on it. That doesn&amp;rsquo;t bother me much as I didn&amp;rsquo;t set any deadline&#xA;expectations, but from time to time I still sigh and think about it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A while ago I had a chat with a friend who told me the following:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Summary March 2021</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2021/03/summary-march-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 10:14:11 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2021/03/summary-march-2021/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was hesitating whether I should write anything for March or not. In the end I decided to actually write a few lines.&#xA;March was completely neutral. Nothing happened. Nothing worth mentioning. Just life. That&amp;rsquo;s it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Summary February 2021</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2021/03/summary-february-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 08:11:07 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2021/03/summary-february-2021/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was hoping that the biggest event of February would be puppy school, but Covid took the lead bringing down both myself,&#xA;and my whole family after me.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After months of light isolation and very few meetings with family and friends, I decided to go to a Krav Maga group&#xA;training. It was hell of a physical training. Ten minutes after the start I could barely catch my breath, and only half&#xA;an hour later after the warm-up was finished, I managed to sync my breathing. Overall training was really good, nice&#xA;people. After moving out of London, I&amp;rsquo;ve been comparing every martial arts trainer to the one I had there. I did wing&#xA;chun adapted to street fighting, and couldn&amp;rsquo;t find anything even close to that here in Tallinn. Krav Maga came the closest.&#xA;And so after a single session I contracted Covid and have been staying at home for the whole February (and more).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Crossing the Rubicon</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2021/02/crossing-the-rubicon/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2021 21:01:51 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2021/02/crossing-the-rubicon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Every now and then I keep hearing the phrase &amp;ldquo;crossing the Rubicon&amp;rdquo;, yet I have never actually thought about its&#xA;origins and meaning. In &amp;ldquo;Meditations: a new translation&amp;rdquo; Gregory Hays mentioned that event and explains it. Here is&#xA;an exerpt from Wikipedia:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Julius Caesar&amp;rsquo;s crossing the Rubicon river in January 49 BC precipitated the Roman Civil War, which ultimately led to Caesar becoming dictator and the rise of the imperial era of Rome. Caesar had been appointed to a governorship over a region that ranged from southern Gaul to Illyricum (but not Italy). As his term of governorship ended, the Roman Senate ordered Caesar to disband his army and return to Rome. He was explicitly ordered not to bring his army across the Rubicon river, which was at that time a northern boundary of Italy. In January of 49 BC, Caesar brought the 13th legion across the river, which the Roman government considered insurrection, treason, and a declaration of war on the Roman Senate. According to some authors, he is said to have uttered the phrase &amp;ldquo;alea iacta est&amp;rdquo;—the die is cast—as his army marched through the shallow river. Today, the phrase &amp;ldquo;crossing the Rubicon&amp;rdquo; is a metaphor that means to pass a point of no return.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Summary January 2021</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2021/02/summary-january-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2021 07:58:44 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2021/02/summary-january-2021/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The moment I stop taking notes and leave writing this blog post for a week or two, all my memories of the past month&#xA;events vanish. Partly this is because nothing big happens, and the life is pretty much the same. With a young kid&#xA;every day is almost a groundhog day. Luckily, I can point out few events that made this month stand out a bit&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;About 5 years ago I moved back to Tallinn from London and decided to start a honey business. I was buying in raw unfiltered&#xA;honey, creaming it, adding dried berries and berry syrup, and selling this online. It was slowly picking up pace, but was&#xA;way too slow to make it sustainable for me. In the end I also lost inspiration, and so decided to quit. Selling the 50l&#xA;creamer took the longest, and I have finally sold it this January.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Two Launches on Producthunt</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2021/01/two-launches-on-producthunt/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2021 12:31:31 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2021/01/two-launches-on-producthunt/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last week I launched &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.getshipit.com&#34;&gt;shipit&lt;/a&gt; (a tool for product managers to help plan and manage their product) on Product Hunt for the second time. I hesitated whether I should do it or not, but the results were very unexpected.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/producthunt/launch.png&#34; alt=&#34;shipit on Product Hunt&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I spent nearly two weeks preparing the first round, reading about the timing, the importance of famous hunters, your first comment, and the support of community. I failed to find someone to hunt us, so did it myself. During the day I was asking every single person I know to upvote it, including our clients. As a result, I think it became #2 (or #3) product of the day, brought ~1500 visits to the website, some buzz, and zero conversions. My friends launching &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.producthunt.com/posts/modash-influencer-search&#34;&gt;Modash&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.producthunt.com/posts/outfunnel-2&#34;&gt;Outfunnel&lt;/a&gt; might have had slightly better results, but nothing extraordinary.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On Algorithms and Manipulation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2021/01/on-algorithms-and-manipulation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2021 20:24:51 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2021/01/on-algorithms-and-manipulation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Few years ago there was a &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2015_San_Bernardino_attack&#34;&gt;mass-shooting&lt;/a&gt; in San Bernardino.&#xA;FBI seized the phone of one of the shooters and asked Apple to decrypt it. Apple refused citing the protection of its&#xA;users not matter what. Ask any person on the street or among your friends who is right here, and the would most likely&#xA;side with the FBI. After all, a person who massacred 14 people by definition cannot have the right to privacy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Summary December 2020</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2020/12/summary-december-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Dec 2020 08:11:51 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2020/12/summary-december-2020/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It looks like December has been the most fruitful and event-rich month of the year.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;dog&#34;&gt;Dog&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve always wanted to have a dog, and about 4 years when I realized things are going sour with my finances, and&#xA;the investments I made are going to require most of my money, I had to put the idea of owning a dog away. Since few&#xA;months ago after I got rid of that project, the thought of owning a dog started to become more real. But which breed?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Summary November 2020</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2020/12/summary-november-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Dec 2020 08:10:48 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2020/12/summary-november-2020/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Another monthly update that I wanted to write in the beginning of the month before forgetting everything. Life with two small kids is becoming more and more complicated.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Funny how the opinion on 1 vs 2 kids changes from meh, that&amp;rsquo;s easy, and I have lots of energy and free time, and we can have a third kid in the first month. Then in the second month things start to settle down and you have less energy, but still capable of following all your life activities like sports, hobbies, etc. And then it hits you. In November it dawned on me that all my hobby projects (RC car, reading) and sports (climbing and freelethics) can be put aside for 6-12 months at least. That&amp;rsquo;s the reality of having a bigger family.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Summary October 2020</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2020/10/summary-october-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Oct 2020 14:43:06 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2020/10/summary-october-2020/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What happens when something drags you for so long that you forget what the normal life looks like? When you have a&#xA;constant buzz in your ear, or a never-ending pain in the shoulder, you get used to living with that. Likewise I got&#xA;involved in an extremely bad investment 5 years ago that changed the course of my life considerably.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I got invited by a family friend to participate in a project, and I approved of it to one of my close family members.&#xA;The person asking for the money had a good business track record and we knew him for a very long time, which was the&#xA;main reason I took my guards off and haven&amp;rsquo;t done any due diligence whatsoever. In the course of the next few years&#xA;the project went from nice to sour, original owner disappeared, and I managed to get the ownership. After that I poured&#xA;in huge amount of cash (going into debt) in order to try and save it. In the process I got robbed and betrayed several&#xA;times more due to me trusting people. Finally few weeks ago I managed to sell it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Summary September 2020</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2020/10/summary-september-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Oct 2020 14:31:43 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2020/10/summary-september-2020/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When you miss the deadline for writing a regular blog post and haven&amp;rsquo;t left any notes, it becomes really hard to remember&#xA;what happend in that month. Nothing special, I guess, since I don&amp;rsquo;t remember much. But here are a few notes&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My RC car project got stalled for quite a while for various reasons. After disassembling the chassis I started modelling&#xA;new motor mounts to support a motor for each wheel. Turned out that not only I needed a new mount system, but I also need&#xA;to redo the drive chafts too. And&amp;hellip; I just couldn&amp;rsquo;t figure out how to take these apart. As a result, zero progress in&#xA;September here.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Summary August 2020</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2020/09/summary-august-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Sep 2020 14:56:46 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2020/09/summary-august-2020/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Having your first child changes everything in life. Eventually you adapt to the new lifestyle. New habits develop. You learn&#xA;to better plan your time if you want some personal space. Then the second child arrives and everything changes again. You go&#xA;through the same process again. I kind of expected it won&amp;rsquo;t be easy, but didn&amp;rsquo;t know in which way. In every way!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Having a second child was a huge event in August, but there are other things that happened as well: August ended with me&#xA;doing sports for two months. Initially I planned to have it 6 times a week which turned out to not be realistic. First&#xA;month saw me doing 3-5 training sessions per week (talking about 30-40 min freelethics) while this month was between 3-4.&#xA;Nevertheless, I managed to do it and can see visible progress. My belly reduced in size and I can feel, and most importantly see&#xA;my abs now. Far from having a 6-pack, but still visibly pleasant.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Summary July 2020</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2020/08/summary-july-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 22:56:41 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2020/08/summary-july-2020/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;July has been another interesting month in my startup life. My co-founder has moved back to his home country leaving me alone in Estonia. Not that it&amp;rsquo;s a big deal and means an end to our company, but it&amp;rsquo;s still a bit of a blow to the social part of the company. Now it became remote-only with all three co-founders spread across Europe.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We haven&amp;rsquo;t had any new customers in July, but I started turning more attention to marketing and sales. I hate social networks, yet I feel like these are the key to some success, especially Twitter and LinkedIn. While making honey desserts, Instagram was responsible for 90% of the sales I made, here I think Twitter can be that driver. I&amp;rsquo;m yet to crack the code for that in August.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Summary June 2020</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2020/06/summary-june-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2020 09:34:09 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2020/06/summary-june-2020/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My sports habits continued in June and I have been going to the climbing gym throughout the whole month. As a result&#xA;my climbing problem skills went from the simple 1-3 (using French &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.guidedolomiti.com/en/rock-climbing-grades/&#34;&gt;grading system&lt;/a&gt;)&#xA;to starting doing 4-grade problems. Each session is followed up with some fitness excersizes. It helps to train with&#xA;a buddy as you are constantly pushed to rest less, train more, and climb increasingly more complex routes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Summary May 2020</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2020/06/summary-may-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2020 08:54:22 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2020/06/summary-may-2020/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;May saw the relaxing of the quarantine rules, and at the beginning of the month restaurants started to open up. We went to one and were the only people there.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;While I was in high school I used to ride a dirt bike. These were fun times and in the process I made some good friends and broke a few bones and had several brain concussions. This bike was in my parents&amp;rsquo; garage since then, until I sold it few weeks ago. I had it for nearly 17 years! It was purchased by the 16-year old nutcase that resembled me a lot around the same age. I also sold my city bike and didn&amp;rsquo;t plan on buying a new one, but my child got a new bicycle for her birthday and in a few days it was impossible to chase her. So I made a rush decision to buy a&amp;hellip; well, full-suspension bike because it was a very rational decision. Pretty much all of my most expensive purchases are made in a rush. But these also make me happiest.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why you shouldn&#39;t become an angel investor</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2020/05/why-you-shouldnt-become-an-angel-investor/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2020 09:40:31 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2020/05/why-you-shouldnt-become-an-angel-investor/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For many people like me, angel investing is akin to being a pirate. You sail the vast seas in search of the Urca de Lima of startups. Every encounter with the navy ship (the WeWork of our time) can cause you your life,get decapitated, or your team turns against you and leave on a deserted island with just a single bottle of rum. But every once in a while some pirate (which could be you) hit that cargo ship with gold bullion. And you&amp;rsquo;re set for life. Pirates are  strong, courageous, smart, and they always have beautiful women around them. This is how I viewed angel investors. Until recently.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Summary April 2020</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2020/05/summary-april-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2020 09:07:15 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2020/05/summary-april-2020/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;April was the second month of the pandemic and lockdowns here in Estonia. We were already staying at home since the end&#xA;of February, so not much has changed. It took a way longer than I hoped for to adapt to the new work-life balance.&#xA;As a result, I moved to a somewhat flexible working hours, several smaller chunks with longer breaks instead of a one&#xA;long 9-5 day. When you have two working adults and a toddler, it&amp;rsquo;s next to impossible to do deep work unless you wake up&#xA;very early in the morning (which I don&amp;rsquo;t). But here might lie another shifting habit for me: these days it&amp;rsquo;s really hard&#xA;to wake up early and become productive right away. I don&amp;rsquo;t have morning rituals like coffee and paper, yoga, or cold&#xA;shower, but I might try something different: to have a short walk in the forest instead, or maybe a jog. All my big changes&#xA;started in the middle of the week, month, year. I never started something from next Monday. So this might be the same.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Summary March 2020</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2020/03/summary-march-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Mar 2020 16:12:23 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2020/03/summary-march-2020/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well, March and likely next few months are going to be all about the virus, self-isolation, and remote work. Both me&#xA;and my wife have IT-related jobs which are easy to make remote. I&amp;rsquo;ve been working remotely for the past 5 years so it&amp;rsquo;s&#xA;nothing new. What is different though is that our kiddo is also staying home with us, and it&amp;rsquo;s been nightmare&amp;rsquo;ish, to say&#xA;the least.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the past two weeks we&amp;rsquo;ve all been adapting to the new reality: trying to find time and space for some deep work,&#xA;getting personal time and space outside work, and having enough ideas and games to get the toddler busy and entertained.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Walk Around Pelgulinn</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2020/03/a-walk-around-pelgulinn/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2020 22:34:22 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2020/03/a-walk-around-pelgulinn/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Tallinn is divided into 8 districts which in turn are sub-divided into smaller parts. While everyone who lives in the city they were born think they know the place, tourists and expacts usually know way more. When I lived in London I loved to explore tiny villages that the city eventually consumed. When you arrive there the place still feels like a village. In a series of blog posts I want to explore my own city&amp;rsquo;s sub districts and map them here.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reading</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2020 20:02:21 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reading/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;reading-queue&#34;&gt;Reading queue&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Living_My_Life&#34;&gt;Living My Life&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; by Emma Goldman&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;John Toland&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://archive.org/details/letterstoserena00tolagoog&#34;&gt;Letters to Serena&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://crimethinc.com/books/days-of-war-nights-of-love&#34;&gt;Days of War, Nights of Love&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; Crimethink for Beginners&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Momo_(novel)&#34;&gt;Momo&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; by Michael Ende&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Letters_to_a_Young_Poet&#34;&gt;Letters to a Young Poet&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; by Rainer Maria Rilke&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Feynman_Lectures_on_Physics#Six_Easy_Pieces_(1994)&#34;&gt;Six easy pieces&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; by Richard Feinman&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Thing_Explainer&#34;&gt;Thing Explainer&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; by Randall Munroe&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/268266.Thinking_Physics&#34;&gt;Thinking Physics&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; - by Lewis Carroll Epstein&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Story_of_Philosophy&#34;&gt;The story of Phylosophy&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; - by Will Durant&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Beginning_of_Infinity&#34;&gt;The Beginning of Infinity&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; - by David Deutsch&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Fabric_of_Reality&#34;&gt;The Fabric of Reality&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; - by David Deutsch&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Masters-Disaster-Commandments-Damage-Control/dp/113727896X&#34;&gt;Masters of Disaster: The Ten Commandments of Damage Control&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; - by Christopher Lehane&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;currently-reading&#34;&gt;Currently reading&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Genome-Autobiography-Species-23-Chapters/dp/0060894083&#34;&gt;Genome: The Autobiography Of A Species In 23 Chapters&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; by Matt Ridley&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Greatest_Story_Ever_Told%E2%80%94So_Far&#34;&gt;The Greatest Story Ever Told - So Far&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;read&#34;&gt;Read&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.penguinrandomhouse.com/books/6367/meditations-by-marcus-aurelius/&#34;&gt;Meditations: a new translation&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo;, translated by Gregory Hays&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/311696.Ami_el_ni_o_de_las_estrellas&#34;&gt;Ami: child of the stars&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo;  by Enrique Barrios&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Lessons_of_History&#34;&gt;The Lessons of History&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; by Will Durant&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Catch-22&#34;&gt;Catch 22&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; by Joseph Heller&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Divine_Comedy&#34;&gt;Divine comedy&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; by Dante Alighieri&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Summary - February 2020</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2020/02/summary-february-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2020 10:51:20 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2020/02/summary-february-2020/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Being a cold loving person I recently saw a temperature map of Europe showing that throughout the whole continent it&amp;rsquo;s above zero. To say that I was shocked is understatement.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/temperature-map-europe.gif&#34; alt=&#34;temperature map of Europe&#34; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In my memory this is the first winter ever without any snow. Not only that, but we&amp;rsquo;ve got flowers blooming in February! Whenever I take my child to the kindergarten we count how many different types of flowers we spot. The last time it&amp;rsquo;s been &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Galanthus&#34;&gt;galanthuses&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tussilago&#34;&gt;coltsfoots&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Leucojum&#34;&gt;leucojums&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s a fun 15 minute walk but I would rather prefer to pull my child on the sledge rather than explore the spring flora. And so I decided to get some snow and head over to the north of Finland.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2020 16:43:35 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;shipit&#34;&gt;Shipit&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.getshipit.com&#34;&gt;shipit&lt;/a&gt; is a startup that I co-founded with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.quack.ch/&#34;&gt;Till&lt;/a&gt;. Its goal is to help product managers plan their roadmaps and manage the whole product lifecycle, from receiving customer feedback to prioritization and presentation.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;elm-bits-on-pause&#34;&gt;Elm Bits (on pause)&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A &lt;a href=&#34;https://elmbits.com/&#34;&gt;newsletter&lt;/a&gt; about everything related to Elm programming language. After finding out about this tech I got really excited about functional programming and wanted to learn more about the language. Every week I shared the news, articles, and other bits with subscribers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2020 15:44:01 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/me.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;this is me&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hello, my name is Artjom (which is pronounced as &amp;ldquo;artiom&amp;rdquo;).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I am technical co-founder of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.getshipit.com&#34;&gt;getshipit.com&lt;/a&gt; which is a tool to help product managers plan their roadmap and manage product lifecycle. At the moment of this writing (Feb 2020) we&amp;rsquo;re still a tiny company where I&amp;rsquo;m involved in everything: from writing code to customer support, advertising, planning.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://elmbits.com&#34;&gt;Elm Bits&lt;/a&gt; is my weekly email with everything about the Elm programming language. I started that as a way to learn more about the language and functional programming in general.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Startup Perks and Benefits</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2018/10/startup-perks-and-benefits/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Oct 2018 10:39:12 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2018/10/startup-perks-and-benefits/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I work for a startup called Juggle Jobs. We’re the goto place to people to find flexible work. We help early parents to find a challenging part-time work so they could spend the early months with their newborns and not feel a massive hole in their family budget. We help people find a job in multiple companies at the same time, something we call a portfolio career, where you spend several days a months at a company, for example, as their CFO.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using Wtforms With Selectfield and Fieldlist</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2016/10/using-wtforms-with-selectfield-and-fieldlist/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2016 15:30:45 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2016/10/using-wtforms-with-selectfield-and-fieldlist/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;WTForms is an amazing library that helps with the forms creation, validation, rendering. Instead of validating each field separately in your code, all you need to do is run &lt;code&gt;form.validate()&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;selectfield&#34;&gt;SelectField&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Using WTForms is straightforward for most common fields, however when the use-case gets a bit complicated, the documentation is not of much help. Recently I had to create a project with a lot of dynamic fields and validation where I used &lt;code&gt;SelectField&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;SelectMultipleField&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;FieldList&lt;/code&gt; among others. Here is the most basic usage example for creating a form:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
